Register of the Vladimir Konstantinovich Bukovskiĭ papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Editors, Publishers, and Public Speakers Bureau Files, 1978-1999
  - Ethics and Public Policy Center, Washington D.C, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 17: 12)
  - Fitzroy Dearborn Publishers, London, England, 1996 (Box-folder 17: 13)
  - Giangiacomo Feltrinelli Editore, Milan, Italy, 1979 (Box-folder 17: 15)
  - Gustav Lubbe Verlag GmbH, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - The H. W. Wilson Company, New York, New York, 1988 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - Historical Research Foundation, 1995 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Hoover Institution Press, Stanford, California, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 18: 4-5)
  - Institut d'histoire sociale, Paris, France, 1996 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - Intercollegiate Studies Institute Inc., Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania, 1988 (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - John Murray Publishers Ltd., 1998-1999 (Box-folder 18: 8-10)
  - Katalizátor Iroda, Budapest, Hungary, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 18: 11)
  - Kidd, Rapinet, Badge & Co. and Yarde & Loader, London, Great Britain, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - Miroslaw Latkowska Publishing House Volumen, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 18: 13)
  - National Review, New York, New York, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 18: 14)
  - The New Republic, Washington, D.C., 1991 (Box-folder 18: 15)
  - The New York Times, Athens, Greece, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 18: 16)
  - Open Court Publishing Company, 1988 (Box-folder 18: 17)
  - Opera Mundi s. a., Paris, France, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
  - Penley Milward & Bayley, 1983 (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - Polonia Book Fund Ltd., London, England, 1986 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - Random House Inc., New York, New York, 1995 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - The Reader's Digest, New York, New York, 1988 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - Regnery Publishing Inc., Washington, D.C., 1997-1998 (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - The Richmond News Leader, 1991 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - The Romanian Cultural Foundation, Bucharest, Romania, 1996 (Box-folder 17: 14)
  - Royce Carlton Inc., New York, New York, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 19: 9)
  - Schaeffer V Productions Inc., Los Gatos, California, 1983 (Box-folder 19: 10)
  - Seewald Verlag, Stuttgart, Germany, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - Social Philosophy Policy Center, Bowling Green, Ohio, 1992 (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - Spoeczny Instytut Wydawniczy ZNAK, Krakow, Poland, 1999 (Box-folder 19: 13)
  - Thomas Nelson Publishers, Nashville, Tennessee, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 19: 14)
  - Times Newspapers Ltd., London, England, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19: 15)
  - University Press of America Inc., Lanham, Maryland, 1987-1996 (Box-folder 19: 16)
  - The Viking Press (Viking Penguin Inc.), New York, New York, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 19: 17)
  - Verlag Ulstein GmbH, Berlin, Germany, 1983 (Box-folder 19: 18)
  - The Washington Institute for Values in Public Policy, Washington, D.C., 1986-1987 (Box-folder 19: 19)
  - The Washington Quarterly, Washington, D.C., 1988 (Box-folder 19: 20)
  - William Morrow & Company Inc. Publishers, 1985 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Writers in Prison Committee, International PEN, London, 1996 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Yale University Press, New Haven, Connecticut, 1998 (Box-folder 20: 3)
- Legal Records, 1973-1993
  Material from Bukovskiĭ's defamation cases against publishers. Includes correspondence, legal papers, clippings, and other materials relating to libel cases.
  - The Guardian, 1973-1984 (Box-folder 20: 4-11)
  - New Scientist, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 20: 12)
  - The Nation, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 27: 14-18, Box-folder 28: 1-2)
  - The New Times, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 21: 1-3)
  - Trud, 1986 (Box-folder 28: 3)
- International Human Rights Organizations File, 1978-1998
  Arrangement Statement
  Arranged alphabetically by name of organization.
  - Andrei Sakharov Institute, 1983-1985
    - General, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 27: 1)
      Includes "Notes on Proposal to Create the Sakharov Institute" and collected clippings on Andrei Sakharov's political activity.
    - Annual financial statement, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 2)
    - Conference at Hoover Institution, Stanford University, 1984 September 14 and 15 (Box-folder 27: 3)
      Includes a list of participants, agenda, notes, and clippings.
    - International Andrei Sakharov Day, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 4)
      Includes correspondence, a proposal, and clippings.
    - Meeting of the Directors, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 5)
    - Proposal for a Soviet Studies Research Center, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 27: 6)
    - Statement of financial condition, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Center for Appeals for Freedom, 1983 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Center for Democracy, New York, 1983-1991
    - Annual meeting minutes, 1986 (Box-folder 27: 9)
      Includes annual report.
    - Corporate resolutions, 1985 (Box-folder 27: 10)
    - Printed matter, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 27: 11)
      Includes press releases, brochures, and clippings.
    - Program report, 1986 (Box-folder 27: 12)
    - Statement by Russian coal miners, 1991 (Box-folder 27: 13)
  - Center for Public Diplomacy Studies, 1986 (Box-folder 28: 4)
    Correspondence and clippings.
  - Club de Paris: de la dissidence à la démocratie, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 28: 5)
    Includes organization’s charter and correspondence.
  - Committee for Defense of Soviet Armenian Political Prisoners, Los Angeles, circa 1985 (Box-folder 28: 6)
    Includes a declaration and an appeal.
  - Conservative Alliance, Alexandria, Virginia, 1984 (Box-folder 28: 7)
    Includes The Human Rights and National Survival Program of 1984.
  - European Liaison Group, London, England, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 28: 8-10)
    Includes correspondence regarding Andrei Sakharov, memoranda, and "Chairman's Report for 1983."
  - Fighting Solidarity, Warsaw, Poland, 1982-1991 (Box-folder 30: 4-8)
    Includes correspondence and materials of Warsaw conference on establishing a coordinating center of radical parties and political organizations to support the international human rights movement.
  - Freedom of Communication, Jersey City, New Jersey, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 28: 11)
    Includes a proposal, correspondence, and a newsletter.
  - Freedom Party, Wroclaw, Poland, 1990 (Box-folder 30: 2)
    Includes correspondence and statements.
  - Friends of the Democratic Center in Central America (PRODEMCA), 1985-1986 (Box-folder 28: 12)
    Includes correspondence, memoranda, a statement, and clippings.
  - Helsinki Watch, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 28: 13)
    Includes correspondence, memoranda, and statements.
  - Iceberg, Artistic Association of Former Dissidents, Moscow, Russia, 1991-1998
    - Organizational charter, 1991 (Box-folder 28: 14)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1998
      - Belyshev, Andrei, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 28: 15)
      - Dubovenko, B. B., 1991 (Box-folder 29: 1)
      - Idolenko, V. I., 1996-1998 (Box-folder 29: 2)
      - Kuzin, Viktor, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 29: 3)
      - Moskovchenko, N. M., 1997 (Box-folder 29: 4)
      - Paasilinna, Reino, 1992 (Box-folder 29: 5)
      - Pack, Michael, 1992 (Box-folder 29: 6)
      - Person, Bo, 1992 (Box-folder 29: 7)
        Includes materials relating to contract with Russian Central Television on production documentaries about the human rights movement.
  - The International Committee on Behalf of Armando Verdiglione, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 29: 8)
    Includes correspondence and printed matter.
  - International Freedom Foundation, Washington, D.C., 1991-1992 (Box-folder 29: 9)
    Includes 1991 Annual Report.
  - Jubilee Campaign, 1990 (Box-folder 29: 10)
    Includes newsletter and other material relating to "British Response to Moscow Food Crisis."
  - Moscow Helsinki Group (Moscow Helsinki Watch Group), 1982-1985 (Box-folder 29: 11)
    Correspondence and statements.
  - Mouvement de Liberation Bulgare, Paris, 1983 (Box-folder 29: 12)
    Includes organizational background, purposes and activity, draft of annual budget, and staff information.
  - National Endowment for Democracy (NED), 1983-1993
    - Annual report, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 29: 13, Box-folder 29: 21)
    - Establishment of the organization, 1983 (Box-folder 29: 14)
    - Newsletter of the NED, 1993 (Box-folder 29: 15)
    - Proposals for the NED by Bukovskiĭ, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 29: 16)
    - Remarks given by Carl S. Gershman, President, the National Endowment for Democracy at the Human Rights Day Ceremony, The White House, 1984 (Box-folder 29: 17)
    - Romanian Liberty Institute Final Report, 1986 (Box-folder 29: 18)
    - Statement of Principles and Objectives, 1983 (Box-folder 29: 19)
    - Talking Points, 1983 (Box-folder 29: 20)
    - The Unfinished Revolution: Proceedings of the National Endowment for Democracy's Third International Conference on Democracy, Washington, D.C., 1991 (Box-folder 29: 22)
  - National Forum Foundation, 1985 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Resistance International (RI) files, 1980-1996
    - Organizational records, 1983-1994
      Includes legal papers, statement of principles, program, minutes, activity reports, financial papers, and clippings, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
      - Activity proposals and reports, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 21: 4-6)
        Includes the 1991 annual report and correspondence.
      - Board of directors meetings minutes, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 21: 7)
      - Budget estimates and financial statements, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 21: 8)
      - Bylaws, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 21: 9)
      - Clippings, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 21: 10-11)
        Contains newspaper clippings collected by the creator, relating to the activities of the organization.
      - Correspondence, 1981-1993
        - General, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 22: 1)
        - Berns, Elizabeth, 1985 (Box-folder 22: 2)
        - Dobriansky, Lev E., 1994 (Box-folder 22: 3)
        - Estekov, Almaz, 1990 (Box-folder 22: 4)
        - Gluza, Zbigniew, 1994 (Box-folder 22: 5)
        - Grocholski, S., 1983-1984 (Box-folder 22: 6)
        - Holzer, Henry Mark, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 22: 7)
          Includes material relating to the Bukovskiĭ libel case against Victor Kamkin Inc. and New Times.
        - Humanitas International Human Rights Committee (Joan C. Baez), 1985 (Box-folder 22: 8)
        - Huuhtanen, Pirkko, 1981 (Box-folder 22: 9)
        - Ignats, Ulo, 1983 (Box-folder 22: 10)
        - Jolis, Albert E., 1983-1992 (Box-folder 22: 11-13)
        - Kaplan, Foger F., 1983-1984 (Box-folder 22: 14)
        - Kazakov, G., and V. Idolenko, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 22: 15)
        - Kelly, Petra K., 1986 (Box-folder 22: 16)
        - Kung, Andres, 1985 (Box-folder 22: 17)
        - Kuznetsov, Eduard, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 22: 18)
        - Larsson, Anders, 1985 (Box-folder 22: 19)
        - Makarenko, Mikhail, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 22: 20)
          Includes memoranda, minutes, and clippings relating to Resistance International activities in the United States.
        - Montinola, Ching, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 22: 21)
        - Pell, Elliott L., 1988 (Box-folder 22: 22)
        - Reagan, Ronald, 1985 (Box-folder 22: 23)
        - Richardson, Randolph R., 1985 (Box-folder 22: 24)
        - Rock, Alan W., 1984 (Box-folder 22: 25)
        - Roth, Allen, 1985 (Box-folder 22: 26)
        - Salvatori, Henry, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 22: 27)
        - Silber, John R., 1986 (Box-folder 22: 28)
          Includes "Testimony of John R. Silber, President, Boston University, before the Committee on Foreign Relations of the United States Senate."
        - Singlaub, John K., 1984 (Box-folder 22: 29)
        - Svitsova, Olga, 1984 (Box-folder 22: 30)
        - Tyson, James, 1984 (Box-folder 22: 31)
        - Weisblatt, Karen, 1986 (Box-folder 22: 32)
          Includes "Trip Report to Kiev, April 13 - May 1, 1986," by Weisblatt.
        - Wick, Charles Z., 1987 (Box-folder 22: 33)
      - General Assembly of Resistance International (creation of the organization), Paris, 1983 (Box-folder 23: 1-2)
        Includes Bukovskiĭ's address "To the Participants of the Paris Conference of the Resistance International," correspondence, proposals, and clippings.
      - Staff meeting minutes, 1984 (Box-folder 23: 3)
      - Statement of principles, 1983 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - Special projects file, 1980-1996
      - Anti-communist movements in the Third World, 1983-1984
        - General, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 23: 5-6)
          Includes correspondence, proposals, and reports on Central America project.
        - Angolan Civil War, 1983-1986
          Includes material relating to propaganda work among the Cuban troops deployed in Angola.
          - Correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 23: 7-8)
            Includes letters and photographs from Efim (Chaim) Iudin and Larisa Vilenskaia.
          - Reports on political and social issues, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 23: 9-11)
            Reports by organization representatives in Angola: Viktor Raginskii, Larisa Vilenskaia, and Vera Popova. Includes group photographs depicting members of the National Union for the Total Independence of Angola (UNITA).
          - Clippings, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 23: 12)
        - Cuba, 1983
          - Film project, 1986 (Box-folder 23: 13)
            Includes organization’s appeal to the President of UNITA (The National Union for the Total Independence of Angola) General Jonas Savimbi to support the project.
          - Solidarity Campaign, 1983 (Box-folder 23: 14)
        - El Salvador, 1983 (Box-folder 24: 1)
        - Honduras, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 24: 2)
        - Mozambique, 1983 (Box-folder 24: 3)
        - Nicaragua, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 24: 4)
        - Venezuela, 1983 (Box-folder 24: 5)
      - Distribution of Samizdat video cassettes in the Soviet Union, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 24: 6)
        Includes project proposal and clippings.
      - Opposition to the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan, 1980-1996
        - Correspondence, 1982-1984
          - General, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 24: 7)
          - American Aid for Afghans, 1983 (Box-folder 24: 8)
          - Baez, Joan Chandos, 1983 (Box-folder 24: 9)
          - Churchill, Winston Spencer, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 24: 10)
          - Committee for a Free Afghanistan, 1984 (Box-folder 24: 11)
          - Dolan, Anthony R., 1982 (Box-folder 24: 12)
          - Federation for American Afghan Action, 1984 (Box-folder 24: 13)
            Includes memoranda.
          - Fourcade, Marie-Madeleine, 1983 (Box-folder 24: 14)
          - Mitchell, Colin, 1983 (Box-folder 24: 15)
          - Skard, Jon, 1984 (Box-folder 24: 16)
        - Establishment of Radio Free Kabul (RFK), 1982-1985 (Box-folder 24: 17-21)
          Includes proposals, statements, correspondence, reports, and clippings.
        - Printed matter, 1983-1996 (Box-folder 25: 1-2, Box-folder 24: 22-23)
          Includes bulletins, newsletters, and clippings.
        - Soviet prisoners of Afghan war, 1980-1988
          - Correspondence, 1983-1988
            - Albatross Press Agency, 1986 (Box-folder 25: 3)
            - American Aid for Afghans, 1984 (Box-folder 25: 4)
            - Association for a Free Russia, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 25: 5)
            - Bethell, Nicholas William, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 25: 6)
            - Center for Appeals for Freedom, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 25: 7)
              Includes photographs depicting Liudmila Thorn with Soviet soldiers in Afghanistan.
            - Congress of Russian Americans Inc., 1983-1984 (Box-folder 25: 8)
              Includes statements of intent by other Russian émigré organizations.
            - European Liaison Group, 1984 (Box-folder 25: 9)
            - Federation for American Afghan Action, 1985 (Box-folder 25: 10)
            - Freedom House (Liudmila Thorn), 1983-1988 (Box-folder 25: 11-15)
              Includes Soviet defectors' statements, interview transcripts, and biographical notes.
            - Holzer, Henry Mark, 1986 (Box-folder 26: 1)
            - House of Commons, 1984 (Box-folder 26: 2)
            - International Rescue Committee Inc., 1984 (Box-folder 26: 3)
            - International Society for Human Rights Inc., 1983-1984 (Box-folder 26: 4)
            - Makarenko, Mikhail, 1985 (Box-folder 26: 5)
              Includes transcript of press conference given by Makarenko.
            - Orthodox Church in America, 1984 (Box-folder 26: 6)
            - Posthumus & Abols, 1984 (Box-folder 26: 7)
            - Shuster, S., 1983 (Box-folder 26: 8)
          - Clippings, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 26: 9-17)
          - Printed matter, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 26: 18-19)
            Includes Hidden War: The Struggle for Afghanistan, a staff report prepared for the Committee of Foreign Relations, United States Senate, Washington D.C., 1984.
  - Scientists for Sakharov, Orlov and Shcharansky, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 30: 3)
    Includes correspondence, newsletters, and clippings.
  - Stichting Comite Vladimir Boekovski (Vladimir Bukovskii Foundation Committee), 1980-1986
    - Commemorative week on the Great Famine in Ukraine, 1983 (Box-folder 30: 9)
      Correspondence and printed matter.
    - Financial estimates and report, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 30: 10)
    - The Second World Shop, Amsterdam, 1983 (Box-folder 30: 11)
      Correspondence, clippings, and photographs of the opening of a unique bookstore of dissident literature.
    - Statement issued by Robert van Voren after a seven-day trip to Leningrad and Moscow, 1980 (Box-folder 30: 12)
  - Union of Committees of Soldiers’ Mothers (non-governmental soldier's rights organization), 1990-1991 (Box-folder 30: 13-15, Box-folder 31: 1)
    Includes appeals from soldiers and their parents to the Soviet military authorities regarding human rights abuse.
- Subject File, 1979-1981
  Contains addresses, articles, brochures, bulletins, clippings, correspondence, flyers, itinerary, lists, memoranda, messages, minutes of meetings, newsletters, notes, petitions, press releases, printed matter, remarks, reports, statements, testimony, and transcripts, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - The 12th World Festival of Youth and Students in Moscow, 1985 (Box-folder 31: 2)
    Includes correspondence, a program, clippings, and the Communique at the 4th Meeting of the International Preparatory Committee for the 12th World Festival.
  - Alcoholism, crime, and delinquency in Soviet society, 1980-1997 (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - American boycott of the 1980 Olympic Games in Moscow, 1979-1980
    Includes correspondence, writings, clippings, and printed matter.
    - Call by Soviet dissidents to boycott the Olympics, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 31: 4)
    - Comité Olympische Spelen en Mensenrechten conference: Olympic Games and Human Rights, The Hague, 1980 (Box-folder 31: 5)
      Includes an invitation letter, agenda, and working papers.
    - Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 31: 6)
    - Printed matter, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 31: 7-8)
      Includes newsletters, press releases, and clippings.
  - Anglo-Russian Peace Campaign, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 31: 9-10)
    See also: Correspondence series, Cadorgan, Peter.
  - Anti-Defamation Association of Émigré from Post-1917 Russia, New York, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 31: 11)
    Includes statements, correspondence, a balance sheet, and clippings.
  - Bilateral Nuclear Weapons and Human Rights Declaration, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 31: 12)
    Statement, correspondence, and clippings.
  - Campaign for Defense and Multicultural Disarmament, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 32: 1-2)
    Statements, correspondence, newsletters, and clippings.
  - Campaign for a Soviet-Free New Zealand, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 32: 3-5)
    Includes correspondence, media releases, and clippings.
  - Decolonization of the Soviet empire, 1983 (Box-folder 32: 6)
    Includes memo and reports.
  - Democracy movements in the Soviet Union, 1990-1996
    - General, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 32: 7)
    - Democratic Party of Russia (DPR), 1990-1991 (Box-folder 32: 8)
      Includes a charter of declaration of principles and correspondence.
    - Demokraticheskaia Oppozitsiia, Rossiskii blagotvoritel'nyi obshchestvennyi fond, Moscow, 1990 (Box-folder 32: 9)
    - Dvizhenie Net, 1996 (Box-folder 32: 10)
      Includes statements and appeals.
    - Partiia ekonomicheskoi svobody (PES), 1993 (Box-folder 32: 11)
      Includes political campaign plan memo.
    - Shchit, Soiuz Sotsial'noi Zashchity Voennosluzhashchikh, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 32: 12)
      Includes a charter, a program, appeals, correspondence, and printed matter.
    - Vybor Rossii, Block Reformistskikh Sil, 1993 (Box-folder 32: 13)
      Includes program, memoranda, and printed matter.
  - East-West cultural exchange, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 32: 14)
  - Establishment of November 7th as the Day of Sorrow and Irreconcilability, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 32: 15)
    Includes petitions and correspondence.
  - Forced labor in the Soviet Union, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 32: 16-17)
    Includes Bukovskiĭ's testimony for Senator William L. Armstrong.
  - Geneva Summit, 1985-1986
    - "The General Agreement between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on Contacts, Exchanges and Cooperation in Scientific, Technical, Educational, Cultural, and Other Fields,", 1985 (Box-folder 33: 1)
    - The American Bar Association and the Association of Soviet Lawyers, 1985-1986
      - Administrative Agreement between the American Bar Association and the Association of Soviet Lawyers, dated May 2, 1985 (Box-folder 33: 2)
      - Correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 33: 3)
      - Press releases and clippings, 1986 (Box-folder 33: 4-5)
    - "Agreement on Scientific Cooperation between the National Academy of Sciences of the USA and the Academy of Science of the USSR,", 1986 (Box-folder 33: 6)
  - "Heidelberg Appeal to Heads of States and Governments,", 1992 (Box-folder 33: 7)
    Includes the appeal, a signature list, and correspondence.
  - The Helsinki Accords, 1983-1985
    Includes correspondence, statements, reports, appeals, and clippings.
    - General, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 33: 8-9)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 33: 10)
    - Clippings, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 33: 11-13)
    - Testimony and statements, 1985 (Box-folder 33: 14)
  - Independent Soviet peace movement (Moscow Peace Group), 1982-1984 (Box-folder 34: 1-4)
    Includes appeals, correspondence, statements, clippings, and printed matter.
  - The International Physicians for the Prevention of Nuclear War (IPPNW), Nobel Peace Prize winner, 1985 (Box-folder 34: 5-6)
    Includes correspondence and clippings related to the Novel Peace Prize award to the IPPNW.
  - Kapitsa Fund, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 34: 7-8)
    Includes correspondence and biographical notes on the Russian geographer and Antarctic explorer Andrei Petrovich Kapitsa.
  - Kontinent, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 34: 9)
    Includes A Proposal to Create the Russian Cultural Center in Paris and an Active Kontinent Documentation Center in New York Affiliated with Freedom House, correspondence, and clippings.
  - Korean Air Lines Flight 007, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 34: 10)
    Includes an appeal by Russian dissidents to build a memorial to the flight victims.
  - Mikhail Gorbachev Nobel Peace Prize controversy, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 34: 11)
  - Moscow mayoral election, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 35: 1-2)
    Includes correspondence, appeals, statements, and other materials relating to Bukovskiĭ's candidacy for election as the Mayor of Moscow.
  - National Center for Excellence in Education vs. Edward D. Lozansky (Free University - Washington, Paris, Moscow), 1988 (Box-folder 35: 3)
    Correspondence and court record.
  - National Peace Academy Campaign, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 35: 4)
    Includes a "Declaration of Findings and Purposes."
  - Nuclear arms control, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 35: 5)
    Correspondence, newsletters, memoranda, and clippings.
  - Nuclear Forces Treaty (INF Treaty) between the United States of America and the Soviet Union, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 35: 6-7)